<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">

<!--

This file is a way to translate the texts needed / used on the cover
using the same .pot/po file and Transifex as the rest of the book.
Place text strings that should be on the cover here.

-->

<chapter label="" id="c-cover-text">
  <title>Free Culture</title>
<!-- Quotes from http://free-culture.cc/jacket/, trimmed to fit on one
     page, for use on the back page of the cover. -->

  <para>
Lawrence Lessig
  </para>

  <para>
How big media uses technology and the law to lock down culture and
control creativity
  </para>

  <para>
<quote><citetitle>Free Culture</citetitle> is an entertaining and
important look at the past and future of the cold war between the
media industry and new technologies.</quote> &mdash; <emphasis>Marc Andreessen,
cofounder of Netscape</emphasis>
  </para>

  <para>
<quote><citetitle>Free Culture</citetitle> goes beyond illuminating
the catastrophe to our culture of increasing regulation to show
examples of how we can make a different future. These new-style heroes
and examples are rooted in the traditions of the founding fathers in
ways that seem obvious after reading this book. Recommended reading to
those trying to unravel the shrill hype around <quote>intellectual
property.</quote></quote> &mdash; <emphasis>Brewster Kahle, founder of the
Internet Archive</emphasis>
  </para>

  <para>
<quote>America needs a national conversation about the way in which
so-called <quote>intellectual property rights</quote> have come to
dominate the rights of scholars, researchers, and everyday citizens. A
copyright cartel, bidding for absolute control over digital worlds,
music, and movies, now has a veto over technological innovation and
has halted most contributions to the public domain from which so many
have benefited. The patent system has spun out of control, giving
enormous power to entrenched interests, and even trademarks are being
misused. Lawrence Lessig's book is essential reading for anyone
who want to join this conversation. He explains how technology and the
law are robbing us of the public domain; but for all his educated
pessimism, Professor Lessig offers some solutions, too, because he
recognizes that technology can be the catalyst for freedom. If you
care about the future of innovation, read this book.</quote> &mdash;
<emphasis>Dan Gillmor, author of <citetitle>We the media</citetitle>,
an book on the collision of media and technology</emphasis>
  </para>
</chapter>
